anotherfriend.com 2016-10-11

# AnotherFriend.com - Privacy

Last updated 26th June 2012

## 1\. We Protect Your Privacy

At anotherfriend.com we have created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to protecting your privacy and to inform you about how we handle your personal information.

This Privacy Statement only applies to transactions and activities in which you engage, and data gathered on anotherfriend.com and any other partner website to whom we may link, but does not apply to any other website or offline point of contact between anotherfriend.com, or any other company, and consumers

This is a legal document which sets out how anotherfriend.com (WebDev Ltd) handles and stores data which identifies you. You should read it in conjunction with our Terms & Conditions and Safety Tips, of which this Privacy Statement forms part. Please review this Privacy Statement periodically as we will modify it from time to time. Each time you visit the Site and provide us with information, by doing so you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Statement at that time.

We confirm that all personal data collected and stored by us is held in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003.

## 2\. Your IP Address

Like most E-commerce Websites, each time you visit the Site, we automatically collect your IP Address on the web page from which you came. In order to administer and optimise the Site for you and to diagnose problems with our Site, we use your IP Address to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information about you. We receive other data from the computer, mobile phone or other device you use to access anotherfriend.com. This may include your IP address, your location, type of browser used or the pages you visit.

## 3\. Cookies

We use small files called "Cookies" to enhance the user experience of the WebDev Ltd service and to track some site activities. Most companies on the Internet use cookies (or similar technological methods), including our advertising partners and the platform. For example, we can use them to know that you are connected to the Site, to help you use the modules and share social or buttons to know when you interact with our advertising partners or platform. If you wish to disable these cookies, the "help" section of your browser will tell you how but this will affect your access to some sections of the Site as you will only be able to browse the Site but will be unable to log on. You can find out more about cookies at www.cookiecentral.com.

## 4\. Information we collect from you

Anotherfriend.com only requests information that it is necessary in order for us to fulfill our obligations to you in providing the Dating service for which you have registered and providing introductions to other interested members. We require visitors to the Site to give us contact information (including their name and email address) and demographic information (like their age, occupation, height) to become a member. We then use this information to contact the visitor when necessary for support or to respond to member's emails. In this way, to protect your privacy, anotherfriend.com acts as a gateway for all messages, so your email address is never revealed and other members can only see the Site user name you have chosen. Thus, this is a two-way private email system which allows you to communicate without having to give your email address to others. The personal profiles that are posted on the Site are available to all visitors’ not just subscribers to the service.

We ask that you do not enter personal information or financial information in to your "Profile" (for example, don’t use your address as your user name, or include your name or address in your "about me" section) because if you do then it may be posted publicly on the Site and the information will then be treated as "demographic information" that is "Public Information".

The Site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control and in order to comply with the provisions of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. All data is stored on highly protected databases, which are amongst the best software available today for secure software transactions. However, visitors should note that while WebDev Ltd makes all reasonable efforts to protect subscribers’ privacy, subscribers should be aware that information disclosed while connected to the Internet is transferred to the WebDev Ltd servers over a publicly available telecommunications network. WebDev Ltd cannot be held responsible, and accepts no liability, for unauthorised access to the public network beyond its reasonable control and all information provided by subscribers is done entirely at the subscribers’ own risk.

Personal data is collected and processed in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 which is a piece of Irish legislation. WebDev Limited processes personal and non-personal data on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we may process personal and non-personal data on a server outside of your own country. We may process personal and non-personal data to provide the Services. Where personal data is collected in a third country but processed and held on our servers in Ireland in order for WebDev Ltd to provide the service for which subscribers have subscribed, please note that any transfer of such data will only be such as is necessary for WebDev Ltd to perform the contract to which the subscriber is party. All such transfers, when taking place within WebDev Limited, are governed by EU- approved Binding Corporate Rules for International Data Transfer. Where such transfers are to a United States affiliate or subsidiary, we shall use reasonable endeavors to procure that such affiliate or subsidiary subscribes to the US “Safe Harbor” principles or such data transfers are governed by the provisions of an EU-approved Standard Form Model Contract for international transfers of data.

## 5\. Information other Sites collect from you.

On this website, we may place links to other websites operated by other parties. When you click on these links and visit other websites, regardless of whether or not they contain our brand-name, or other references to us, you need to be aware that we do not control these websites or their businesses, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to these Websites. Hence, they may collect other information from you and we encourage you to review their individual Privacy Policies.

## 6\. Our Dating Partners.

Anotherfriend.com (WebDev Ltd) partner with and provide the online dating services of the following websites:

  * Irish Times
  * Ireland.com
  * Irish Examiner Group
  * TV3
  * Online.ie
  * Entertainment.ie
  * Beaut.ie
  * 4FM
  * Datefinder
  * Dating.ie

## 7\. How we use Information?

Information we collect from you on registration and during your membership of the Site is used for administrative purposes and to provide you with the anotherfriend.com dating service. By submitting this information you are expressly agreeing to us processing that information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Please remember that due to the nature of the membership of the Site, any information that is disclosed to anotherfriend.com can become public information except in the case of the guarantees of privacy set out below in relation to payments.

We use the information provided by you in order to offer you the service for which you have subscribed. We use your email information and other personal information to operate this Site efficiently and to contact you in relation to your transactions, to forward messages to/from you to/from other members, and to inform you of what is happening on the Site. These "Direct Communications" to you may also contain commercial messages e.g. banner ads, promotional offers etc. "Direct Communications" are an obligatory part of the functioning of this website and receipt of these is a function of Site membership. We use a third-party advertising company to serve ads when you receive “Direct Communications”. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of providing you with “Direct Communications” our third party advertiser may recognise or place a unique “cookie” on your browser. Where third parties act as processors of information on our behalf we require that they comply with our Privacy Statement and the provisions of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003.

WebDev Ltd may as a secondary use of your information, send you "Direct Communications" from sister websites within our group of companies. We may also transfer your data to one of our sister websites within the WebDev Ltd company, namely, [www.maybefriends.com](http://www.maybefriends.com/), [www.singleparents.ie](http://www.singleparents.ie/), [www.irishdatingonline.com](http://www.irishdatingonline.com/), [www.makefriendsonline.com](http://www.makefriendsonline.com/), where of relevance to you.

We do not share your information with any third party except as you may decide to use that information as part of your “Profile”.

You may opt-out from receiving communications from WebDev Ltd (other than those necessary for WebDev Ltd to provide the service for which you have subscribed) or our sister websites at anytime by emailing us at info@anotherfriend.com. This will mean your account is no longer active and you will need to set up a new account with us to avail of our service.

Personal data

This is data that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you and may include your name, address and email address, user IP addresses in circumstances where they have not been deleted, clipped or anonymised and telephone number. We will process any personal data you provide to us to provide the service for which you have subscribed and to manage your membership of the Site and to respond to any communications you might send to us. Some of this personal data which you supply (i.e. information about your lifestyle and health) may be sensitive personal data within the meaning of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. We suggest that you do not supply any data which may fall into the category of sensitive personal data as all information which you submit for inclusion on your “Profile” will be publicly available on the Site. Anotherfriend.com will not disclose any personal data of a sensitive nature without your express consent, except in so far as you have included it on your “Profile”.

Photos – Personal Data includes Photographs of yourself which you may post to the website. Please take care to either post to the Public (viewable by everyone) or Private (you choose who’s view) Gallery depending on your personal preference.

Non-personal data

Like most websites, we gather statistical and other analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of all visitors to the Site. This non-personal data comprises information that cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information regarding, i.e. user IP addresses where they have been clipped or anonymised, browser types and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of the Site.

Non personal data gathered from visitors to the Site in an aggregate form helps us get a better understanding of where our visitors come from and helps us to better design and organise our Site

Please note that we do not pass on our member details to any other entity for marketing purposes.

## 8\. Does WebDev Ltd monitor online behaviour?

Our users communicate with each other through email, chat and SMS. While we do not, as a rule, moderate or monitor users' private exchanges, we reserve the right to do so. Users’ submissions that appear on the public area of the Site can be moderated and, if necessary, we reserve the right to edit, delete/remove or not to use any communication on a public area of the Site.

## 9\. Correct/Update your information

You can access, change or update all your personal information online by logging in as a member, and clicking on "Edit Profile" (this is exclusive of your email address which cannot be amended). You can also unsubscribe to the service by clicking on “deactivate your account”.

## Deleting and Deactivating Your Account

## Deactivation

By disabling your account, you cease all activity.  Other users do not see your profile, but we keep your information so you can re-activate your account in the future. Disabling an account is equivalent to tell us not to remove the information because you may want to use this account in the future.

## Removal

When you request for your account to be ‘permanently deleted’, we remove it completely from our database and site. We do this within 1 working day of receiving an email or written request.  Some information may remain in backup copies and activity logs for up to 90 days.

## 10\. Protect yourself from Spam

It is a good practice to refrain from disclosing your email address or any other personal information in chat rooms, public forums or any other place unless this is properly protected. Information disclosed may be used by other persons for any purpose, including spamming. 

## 11\. Payment Security

Your Credit Card details are secure. We process all payments through a third party provider; Paypal, Realex Payments Ireland or Stripe USA. No credit card details are stored on our servers. All payments are processed on a secure HTTPS payment page.

## 12\. Choice/Opt out

WebDev Ltd regularly sends emails to its members in order to inform them of new services, improvements, etc. Our members can opt out of receiving communications from us by permanently unsubscribing from their membership. To do this you can send an email to info@anotherfriend.com

## 13\. Data Retention Policy

Unless a user has requested their details to be permanently deleted from our system, we hold all records on our system for a period of 7 years. Post this date we contact the member and advise them that their account will be deleted in compliance with our obligation under the Data Protection Act.

## 14\. Contacting our Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of our Site or your dealings with this website, you can contact anotherfriend.com via post, or clicking on the contact us button or by emailing us at info@anotherfriend.com.

## 15\. Right of Access

You have a right to access the personal information that is held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information that anotherfriend.com (WebDev Ltd) holds about you; please write to us at the address set out below enclosing your postal detail and a cheque for €6.35 payable to Anotherfriend.com/WebDev Ltd, 47 O’Connell Street, Limerick, Ireland. Please allow up to 10 working days for your response.

## 16\. Who is WebDev Ltd?

Anotherfriend.com is owned and operated by WebDev Ltd, 47 O’Connell Street, Limerick, Ireland, Company Number 333619.

## 17\. Sale of business

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your personal data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the Site Privacy Statement and provided that the third party only uses your personal data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer. You may inform us of any changes in your personal information and data and in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 we will update or delete your personal data accordingly.

## Revisions to Privacy Statement

Anotherfriend.com (WebDev Ltd) may revise this privacy statement at any time. Changes to this privacy statement will be posted here so you should periodically check this page to review the most recent statement.

We are committed to conducting our business in accordance with these principles in order to ensure that the confidentiality of personal information is protected and maintained.
